迈克:嗨,不要挠我痒痒.我是认真的.喔,
Mike: Hey stop tickling me.I'm serious.Wo, wo, wo.
喔,喔.谢谢你,美好的夜晚.
Thank you for a lovely evening.
吉尔:哦,今晚到此为止吗?
Jill: Oh, it's over?
迈克:是的.我们不能干其他事情了.你花光了钱.嘿,
Mike: Yeah.We can't do anything else.You ran out of money.Hey listen.
听着.我想谢谢你让我开你的新车,琼.
I want to thank youfor letting me drive your new car Joan.
吉尔:吉尔.
Jill: Jill.
迈克:这个名字不适合你.因为我观察你的眼睛,
Mike: That is such a wrong name for you.
我看到你的美丽,
Because I look into your eyes and I see a lovelinessthat makes me want
使得我想叫你琼,琼!
to shout Joan, Joan
吉尔:你真可爱.再见.
Jill: You are so cute.Bye.
迈克:再见.再见.
Mike: Bye.Bye.
琼:你好.
Joan: Hi.
迈克:琼?
Mike: Joan?
琼:是的.
Joan: Yes.
迈克:好的.你是琼.
Mike: Good.You're Joan.
琼:你去哪里了?
Joan: Where have you been?
迈克:我去哪里了?
Mike: Where have I been?
琼:是呀.我十分讨厌等人.
Joan: Yes.I'm sick and tired of waiting around.
你说7点钟在这里见面的.
You said we were going to meet here at seven.
迈克:哦,哦,对,恩.哎,现在只有5点钟.你早来了两个小时.
Mike: Oh.Oh right, uh.Well right now it's only five.You're two hours early.
琼:哦,对不起.
Joan: Oh, I'm sorry.
琼:我的手越来越短了.谢谢你,美好的夜晚.
Joan: My arms are getting shorter.Thanks for a lovely evening.
迈克:啊,早上了.
Mike: Ah, morning.
琼:哇!
Joan: Wow!
迈克:我也很开心.另外顺便说一句,
Mike: I had a lovely time too.
谢谢你让我开你的车,琼.
And by the way, thanks for letting me drive your car Jill.
琼:琼.
Joan: Joan.
迈克:这个名字不适合你.因为我观察你的眼睛,
Mike: That is such a wrong name for you, because when I look into your eyes,
我看到你的美丽,使得我想叫你琼,琼!
I see aloveliness that makes me want to shout Jill.Jill!
琼:她不会吃这套了.
Joan: She's not going to buy that.
琼:我不在乎你我叫什么,随便你叫吧.
Joan: I don't care what you call me.Just call me.
迈克:好.
Mike: Ok.
琼:再见.你真可爱.
Joan: Bye.You're so cute.
迈克:爸爸.
Mike: Dad.
杰森:哦,我这可恶的睡衣被钩在树丛里了.
Jason: Oh, I go to my darn robe caught in the bushes.
那么老房子还很不错,还是?
So the old house is looking pretty good,hu?
迈克:爸爸,你在暗中监视我.
Mike: Dad, you were spying on me.
杰森:我没有暗中监视……
Jason: I wasn't spying...
迈克:是,你监视了.
Mike: Yeah you were.
杰森:父亲不会监视.父亲观察,然后说哇.
Jason: A father doesn't spy.A father observes and goes wow!
迈克:你有嫉妒心理.
Mike: You're jealous.
杰森:我没嫉妒.
Jason: I'm not jealous.
迈克:你心里嫉妒了.
Mike: You're jealous inside.
杰森:我没嫉妒,我碰巧是个结过婚的男人,
Jason: I'm not jealous, I happen to be a married man Mike.
迈克.也碰巧还娶了个好女人呢.别忘了这点.
Happen to be married to a finewoman too.Don't you forget that.
迈克:好.
Mike: Ok.
杰森:为什么我还要是你妈一半岁数的姑娘?啊哈.
Jason: What do I need with a girl half your mothers age?Uh hu.
可别告诉她我说这些.
Don't tell her I said that.
迈克:啊!
Mike: Ahh!
埃迪:啊,米歇尔 西维尔,你真不是个容易找到的人.
Eddie: Ah, Michael Seaver, you are not an easy man to find.
迈克:埃迪,你在这干什么?
Mike: Eddie, what are you doing here?
埃迪:我需要你的主意.是关于我见到的一个姑娘.
Eddie: I need your advice.It's about a girl I'm seeing.
迈克:让她刮毛.
Mike: Tell her to shave.
埃迪:不,不,不.
Eddie: No, no, no.You don't understand.This could be the one.
你不明白.这可能就是那个.这可能就是她.
This could be her.This is thewoman I've been searching for hither and yond.
她就是我到处寻找的女人.米歇尔,我在考虑当这个女人孩子的爸爸.
Michael, I'm considering fathering thiswoman's child.
迈克:那很好,埃迪.
Mike: That's swell Eddie.
埃迪:不,迈克.我已经变了.我不再是那个没救的浪子了.
Eddie: No Mike.I've changed.I am no longer the desperate troller I once was.
迈克:哦.行,那么你在什么地方找到她的?
Mike: Oh.Alright, well where did you find her?
埃迪:我载她去动物园.
Eddie: I picked her up t the zoo.
迈克:埃迪,出去.我累了.
Mike: Eddie, get out.I'm tired.
埃迪:不,不.告诉我一切你所知道有关于话剧方面的知识.
Eddie: No, no.Tell me everything you know about the theatre.
迈克:不.行了.我睡觉了.
Mike: No.Come on.I'm going to bed.
埃迪:迈克,她了解话剧,
Eddie: Mike, she knows about the theatre and if I don't learn this stuff,
如果我不学习这方面的知识的话,这关系就吹了.
this relationship isgone with the wind.
迈克:瞧,埃迪,在十分钟时间里我不能告诉你一切东西.
Mike: Look Eddie, I can't tell you everything in ten minutes.
埃迪:行.还有一个主意.
Eddie: Alright.Another idea.Let's just double date tonight.
今晚我们两个一起去约会.如果她开始唠叨起什么愚蠢的戏剧,我就说"那很不错",
That way if she starts yakkingabout some stupid play and I say "that's neat",
you can say, "What Eddie meant to say was",and put it into theatre words
迈克:那么就像填字游戏?
Mike: What like mezzanine?
埃迪:是,就像那东西.
Eddie: yeah, stuff like that.
迈克:好吧,好吧.
Mike: Ok, ok.
埃迪:好.你对什么食物过敏,我去超级市场买点东西?
Eddie: great.Any food you are allergic to, because I'm going to the market to do theshopping?
迈克:为什么?
Mike: For what?
埃迪:我们的晚餐派对.
Eddie: Our dinner party.
迈克:什么晚餐派对?
Mike: What dinner party?
埃迪:我要做意大利式细面条,埃迪.
Eddie: I am cooking spaghetti Eddie.
迈克:喔喔.
Mike: Woo hoo.
埃迪:那么我三点回来帮你搬家具.
Eddie: So I'll be back about three to help you move the furniture.
迈克:等等.为什么?
Mike: Wait.Why?
埃迪:我告诉她我住的地方很漂亮.这里是垃圾场.
Eddie: Because I told her I lived in a great place.This is a dump.
迈克:你什么意思呀,埃迪?行了,你那地方怎么了?
Mike: What do you mean Eddie?Come on, what's wrong with your place?
埃迪:我的家具当了.
Eddie: My furniture popped.
克莉丝:妈妈.哪里可以哪到更多的肉丸?
Chrissy: Mum.Where do I get more meatballs?
麦琪:克莉丝,你在干什么?
Maggie: Chrissy, what are you doing?
克莉丝:我在为迈克,埃迪和他们的姑娘做饭.
Chrissy: I'm making dinner for Mike, Eddie and their babes.
麦琪:但是亲爱的,你不知道怎么做饭.
Maggie: But honey, you don't know how to cook.
克莉丝:嘘!
Chrissy: Shhh!
迈克:行,汤是否好了?
Mike: Alright, is the soup ready yet?
麦琪:我希望你们两个把这里打扫干净?
Maggie: I hope you two are planning on cleaning this up?
埃迪:哦,西维尔太太,你对这样的一团糟感到生气,是正当的.
Eddie: Oh Mrs.Seaver, you are upset about this mess, and rightfully so.
麦琪:是,我是生气.
Maggie: Yes I am.
埃迪:原谅我.我只是希望克莉丝能够加入,成为我们中一员.但是由于是十块钱,我的臭肉丸在什么地方?
Eddie: So forgive me.I just wanted Chrissy to be included, to be a part
of things.And for tenbucks, where are my stinking meat balls
克莉丝:你遇上比这更大的麻烦了.我把我的创口贴丢进去了.
Chrissy: You got bigger problems than that.I lost a band aid in there.
麦琪:哦,谁把这里打扫干净?
Maggie: Oh, who's going to clean this up?
迈克:听着,我去接我的约会对象了.
Mike: Listen, I got to go pick up my date.
埃迪:去吧.我自己找创口贴.
Eddie: Go.I'll find the band aid myself.
迈克:好吗,妈妈?
Mike: Ok mum.
麦琪:我猜可以.
Maggie: I guess so.
迈克:哦,谢谢你.
Mike: Oh thank you.
麦琪:那么你们正举行宴会?这么复杂?
Maggie: So you boys are throwing a dinner party?How sophisticated.
埃迪:是的,有点.
Eddie: Yeah well sort of.
麦琪:有点.
Maggie: Sort of.
埃迪:是呀,我希望我们不必吃掉纸盘子和果冻罐子.
Eddie: Yeah, I wish we didn't have to eat off the paper plates and jelly jars.
麦琪:真可怜.
Maggie: That's a shame.
埃迪:唉,你想像我这样的人到哪去找纸瓷器和水晶餐具呢?
Eddie: Well where do you expect a guy like me to find fine china and crystal/
麦琪:哦,埃迪,为什么你不用我的?
Maggie: Oh, Eddie, why don't you use mine?
埃迪:真的吗?哦,我不能.
Eddie: really?Oh I couldn't.
麦琪:你当然能.
Maggie: Sure you could.
埃迪:好吧,如果你坚持的话.
Eddie: Well if you insist.
麦琪:只不过是放在这里和收拾垃圾的事情,
Maggie: It's just sitting up here collecting dust and I always feel that
我一直觉得摆设是用餐的一半.
presentation is half themeal.
埃迪:哦.真漂亮,西维尔夫人.
Eddie: Oh.Nice set of flutes Mrs.Seaver.
杰森:恩.意大利细面条.到处都是.
Jason: Hmmm.Spaghetti.Everywhere.
麦琪:知道吗,杰森,20岁的小伙觉得我有魅力.
Maggie: You know Jason, twenty year old men find me attractive.
杰森:谁?
Maggie: Eddie.
麦琪:埃迪.
Jason: Come on.You weren't flattered by Eddie.
Eddie finds anything with a pulse attractive.
杰森:行了.你不能被埃迪阿谀奉承.埃迪觉得一切有脉搏的东西都迷人.
Jason: Who?
麦琪:那么我是有脉搏的东西?
Maggie: So I'm anything with a pulse?
杰森:不,你是我有脉搏的东西.
Jason: No, you're my anything with a pulse.
麦琪:小甜心?
Maggie: Sweetheart?
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:为什么你不尝尝意大利细面条?
Maggie: Why don't you try the spaghetti?
杰森:好呀.
Jason: Yeah.
开萝尔:我今晚不回来吃晚饭了.我有约会.
Carol: I won't be home for dinner tonight.I have date.
也许干旱结束了.倒不是有人关心.
Maybe the drought is over.Not thatanybody cares.
杰森:哦,比平时辣了一点.哦,肉丸里有什么?恩.
Jason: Oh, it's a little spicier than usual.Oh, what's in this ravioli?Hmmm.
迈克:好了,好了,听着.这是我的地方,
Mike: Alright, alright listen.It's my apartment, I live here.
我住这.但是今晚,我不知道这是谁的地方.
But tonight, I don't know whoseplace this is.
约会对象:我们有些共同之处.
Date: we have something in common.
埃迪:不,不,西维尔太太.一个烛台足够了.欢迎到我家来.
Eddie: No, no, Mrs.Seaver.One candelabra is plenty.Welcome to my home.
约会对象:今天光明节?
Date: It's Chanukah?
迈克:啊,对不起.
Mike: Ah, excuse us.Eddie, Eddie, Eddie.
埃迪,埃迪,埃迪.
How in the world did you get my mum to give youall her worldly possessions
你到底使得我妈妈把她所有的宝贝东西都给了你,而她从来不肯给我的.
that she'd never give me?
埃迪:我跟她谈心.像男人一样吸引她.
Eddie: I talked to her.I appealed to her as a person.
顺便说一句,你还知道你妈妈的不顾很不错?
And by the way Mike, do you know thatyour mum has got quite a butt.
迈克:行了.
Mike: Come on.
埃迪:哦,谢谢你提醒我.
Eddie: Oh, thanks for reminding me.
趁我的女人还没到之前,我先赶快下楼准备晚餐.
I've got to hurry downstairs and get dinner before my lady gets here.
你好,我是埃迪.
Hello, I'm Eddie.
蒂娜:我是蒂娜.我可以检查你的心脏吗?不,我下班了.
Tina: I'm Tina.May I check your heart?No, I'm off duty.
埃迪:很明显,你非常专注你的工作.
Eddie: Well you are obviously very dedicated to your craft.
迈克:我们在哪里呢?
Mike: Where were we?
蒂娜:我们谁都不知道.
Tina: Neither one of us knew.
迈克:对对,瞧,
Mike: Right right, see, see this is my apartment,
瞧,这是我的房间,
but Eddie is pretending this is his apartmentbecause there is this girl
但是埃迪谎称这是他的房间,因为他想今晚给那个姑娘留下印象.
that he wants to impress tonight.
蒂娜:你知道,你的发型不错.
Tina: You know, you have a nice head.
迈克:什么?
Mike: Pardon me?
蒂娜:我要走了.再谈谈购物.
Tina: There I go.Talking shop again.
埃迪:事实上,我需要在这垃圾堆住着,
Eddie: Actually I am kind of stuck here in this dump until I can move
直到我自己能够搬出去.
out on my own.
迈克:凯特!
Mike: Kate!
凯特:你好,迈克.
Kate: Hi Mike.
迈克:你在这里干什么?
Mike: What are you doing here?
凯特:好象你不知道一样.
Kate: As if you didn't know.
蒂娜:他不知道.他什么都不知道.
Tina: He doesn't.He doesn't know anything.
埃迪:恩,米歇尔,你知道我女人?
Eddie: Um, Michael, you know my lady?
凯特:你可以这么说.
Kate: You could say that.
迈克:等一下.就这个女人,你想当她的孩子的爸爸.
Mike: Wait a minute.This is the woman, whose children you are going to father?
埃迪:我不明白你哪里会有这样的想法.
Eddie: I don't know where he got that idea.
凯特:迈克,你本可以只是打个电话.
Kate: Mike, you could have just called.
你没有必要让埃迪把我带到来,你有必要吗?
You didn't have to get Eddie to bring me here, did you?
迈克:不,我没有.
Mike: No, I didn't.
凯特:你没有?
Kate: You didn't?
迈克:不.不.我,我,我的确不知道是你和埃迪约会.
Mike: No.No.I, I, I didn't even know it was you who was dating Eddie.
凯特:我只是认为我很难相信.我是说,两个这么好的朋友不讨论他们约会的女人.
Kate: I just find that hard to believe.I mean two guys who are such
good friends don't discussthe women they are dating
迈克:我从来不向埃迪谈论我约会的姑娘,
Mike: I would never talk to Eddie about any woman I was dating,
更别说把他介绍给那些我约会的姑娘了.
let alone introduce him toany woman I was dating.
开凯特:我只是认为……这看起来很自然……哦,没关系.
Kate: Well I just thought....It just seemed natural that...Oh never mind.
迈克:瞧,我知道这样真不舒服,凯特,不过我们是朋友……
Mike: Look, I know this is really uncomfortable Kate, but we are friends...
凯特:只是一次晚餐而已.
Kate: This is just a dinner party.
迈克:对,对.我们是朋友,这是晚餐.为什么不表现的文明点?
Mike: Right, right.We are friends, this is a dinner party.Why not act civilized?
凯特:的确.
Kate: Certainly.
迈克:对.嗨,哦,啊,
Mike: Yes.Hi, well, uh, Eddie, Tina.
埃迪,蒂娜.你们两个也许猜到了,凯特和我约会过.
You both may have guessed that Kate and I have dated.
凯特:而且完全坦白和认真地说,
Kate: And to be totally honest and adult,
我们仍然偶尔见面.
we still do see each other occasionally.
迈克:是的,但是并不意味着什么.
Mike: Yes, but that doesn't mean anything.You know what I...
你们知道……我们俩同时决定和别人约会了.
we both decided at the sametime to see other people.
蒂娜:她甩你?
Tina: She dumped you?
迈克:不.
Mike: No.
埃迪:好了,迈克,过去的事情就过去了.我们能不能只是玩的开心点?
Eddie: Well Mike, what's passed is passed.Can we just have some fun?
凯特:当然.
Kate: Sure.
迈克:好.
Mike: Ok.
蒂娜:好呀.
Tina: Goodie.
凯特:你能把盐递给我吗,亲爱的?
Kate: Could you pass the salt honey?
迈克和埃迪:当然.
Mike and Eddie: Sure.
蒂娜:我们应该被关心吗?他们在手搀手.
Tina: Should we be concerned?They are holding hands.
埃迪:哎.今晚真美妙,嗨,迈克?
Eddie: Ey.This evening is going great, hey Mike?
迈克:是呀.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:本.
Jason: Ben.
本:什么呀?
Ben: What?
杰森:你在我的卧室干什么?
Jason: What are you doing in our bedroom?
本:恩,只是清洁你的双筒望远镜.
Ben: Um, just cleaning your binoculars.
杰森:你在监视迈克,是吗?
Jason: You were spying on Mike, weren't you?
本:爸爸,瞧……
Ben: Dad look...
杰森:本,监视是错误的,就更不必说是不道德和有些不正当.
Jason: Ben, spying is wrong, not to mention immoral and somewhat perverted.
本:比这还糟.
Ben: It's worse than that.
杰森:你什么意思?
Jason: What do you mean?
本:迈克在那和人约会,但是他以前的女朋友凯特和埃迪一起来了.
Ben: Mike is over there with a date, and his old girlfriend Kate just showed up with Eddie.
杰森:不妙……凯特?哟,哟,哟.
Jason: That doesn't make it....Kate?Well, well, well.
本:是,那么你明白我为什么监视了吧?
Ben: Yes, so now you see why I am spying?
杰森:不.我要你回你的房间去,
Jason: No.I want you to go to your room and think about what you did
想想你所做的,和为什么错了.把望远镜留下.
and why it was wrong.And leave the binoculars.
迈克:听着,埃迪,
Mike: Look Eddie, I just wanted to apologize man.
我想道歉,伙计.我是说,
I mean, I think I've been so caught up in my own feelings,
我一心只考虑到我自己的感情,而我忘记了你对这件事有多难过.
that I forgot how weird you must be feeling about all this.
埃迪:我很高兴,没人吃到创口贴.
Eddie: I'm just happy no-one found the Band-Aid.
迈克:埃迪,埃迪,性了.别装了.没关系的.我想让你听我说.我和凯特的关系完了.行了,啊,她不再是我的女朋友.
Mike: Eddie, Eddie, come on.Don't pretend.It's ok.I want you to hear it
with me.Myrelationship with Kate is over.Alright uh, she is no longer my girlfriend
埃迪:很好.我们去吃吧.
Eddie: Great.Let's go and eat.
迈克:我是认真的,伙计.别担心我.我是说,凯特所做的是她自己的事.
Mike: I'm serious man.Don't worry about me.I mean, what Kate does is her business.
埃迪:行.她的事.还有任何碰巧和她有事情能的人……
Eddie: Right.Her business.And whoever happens to go into business with her...
迈克:嗨,你在谈论我……我的前任女朋友.
Mike: Hey, you are talking about my....my ex-girlfriend.
埃迪:哦,迈克.对不起.
Eddie: Oh Mike.I'm sorry.This must be pretty hard for you.
这肯定对你太难了.听着,凯特和我可以回到她的住处.
Listen, Kate and I could go back to her place.
迈克:不!我是说,啊,走.去任何你想去的地方.做任何你想做的事情.行.我把她给你.
Mike: No!I mean, uh, go.Go wherever you want.Do whatever you want.Alright.I give her to you.
埃迪:谢谢.我可以给你点钱吗?
Eddie: Thanks.Can I give you some money?
杰森:哦,天哪!我希望我能读唇.
Jason: Oh man.I wish I could read lips.
麦琪:杰森,亲爱的.你在干什么呢?
Maggie: Jason honey.What are you doing?
杰森:擦你的望远镜.
Jason: Just cleaning your binoculars.
麦琪:我没有望远镜.
Maggie: I don't have any binoculars.
杰森:太糟了,你丢了.
Jason: Too bad.Your loss.
麦琪:杰森,杰森,你在监视迈克,是吗?
Maggie: Jason.Jason, you're spying on mike aren't you.
杰森:不,不.我没监视.
Jason: No, no.I'm not spying.A father doesn't spy.
父亲不会监视.父亲只是观察,然后……喔呵.
A father observes, and thengoes...woohooo!
麦琪:哦,杰森,如果你在他房里干他现在干的事情,而他在这监视你,你会怎么想?
Maggie: Oh Jason, how would you like it if you were in his apartment doing what he is doing  and he were in here spying on you?
杰森:那……哈哈.我讨厌那样.我讨厌那样.真可怕.
Jason: Well...ha ha.I'd hate that.I'd hate that.It's awful.
埃迪:女士们,你们想我们了?
Eddie: Ladies, did you miss us?
蒂娜:嘿嘿嘿.那么,你们和凯特约会多长时间了?
Tina: Hee hee hee.So, how long have you dated Kate?
迈克:两个月.
Mike: Two months.
埃迪:两个星期.我想这是我们第三次约会,蒂娜.
Eddie: Two weeks.I believe this is our third date Tina.
凯特:这是我们的第四次,埃迪.你忘了那次下午在动物园里.
Kate: It's our forth Eddie.You forgot about our afternoon at the zoo.
迈克:哦,就是在那他带你的?
Mike: Oh, is that where he picked you up?
凯特:不.那是他搭我的车的地方.
Kate: No.That's where I picked him up.
那么你们出去多长时间了?
So how long have you two been going out?
蒂娜:是出去还是进来?
Tina: Is this out or in?
迈克:啊,这是我们第一次约会.喔,喔,这么好笑?
Mike: Uh, this is our first date.Wh, wh, what's so funny?
凯特:没什么.仅仅是私人笑话.
Kate: Nothing.It's just a private joke.
迈克:哦.你们介意和我们分享吗?
Mike: Oh.Would you care sharing that with us?
凯特和埃迪:不.
Kate and Eddie: No.
迈克:我说分享,先生.
Mike: I said share Mr.
凯特:你怎么了?我是说,
Kate: What the heck is going on?I mean I thought we agreed to be civilized.
我们答应过要有修养.要像成年人.
To be adults.
迈克:是,可有修养的成年人不会和蠢猪去约会.
Mike: Yeah, well civilized adults do not date rotting pigs.
凯特:你在说什么?
Kate: What are you saying?
迈克:我是说,你对于他来说是太好了.
Mike: I am saying that you are too good for him.
凯特:我认为他是你朋友?
Kate: I thought he was your friend?
迈克:他是我朋友.我不在意他的缺点.
Mike: He is my friend.I overlook his flaws.
凯特:我也一样.跟他在一起,我很快乐.
Kate: Well so do I.I have fun with him.
迈克:快乐!
Mike: Fun!
凯特:是.他人不复杂.迈克,跟他在一起,我很快乐.
Kate: Yeah.He's not complicated.Mike I just have a good time with him.
迈克:哦,哦,但是当我让你开心和快乐的时候,你说我是个害怕长大的大孩子.
Mike: Oh, oh, and when I was just fun and liked to have a good time, you called me a terminal teenager who's afraid to grow up.
凯特:你就是.
Kate: You are.
迈克:哦,我是.我不是.我不是.
Mike: Oh I am.I'm not.I'm not.
凯特:瞧瞧你表演的样子.就像是你希望回到以前还是什么的.
Kate: Look how you are acting.It's like you want to get back together or something.
迈克:不.就此打住.这只是,这只是……
Mike: No.Lets stop right there.It's just, it's just...
凯特:只是什么?
Kate: Just what?
迈克:凯特,行了,我告诉你我在烦恼什么.我所烦恼的是在喜欢我之后,你怎么能够去喜欢埃迪?
Mike: Kate, alright, I'll tell you what's really bothering me.What's really bothering me is how could you possibly like Eddie after having liked me?
凯特:因为我和埃迪的关系没有朝向任何地方.
Kate: Because my relationship with Eddie isn't heading anywhere.
迈克:哦,嗨.我可以指出我们的关系没有朝向任何地方.
Mike: Oh hey.Well may I point out that ours wasn't heading anywhere either.
凯特:我明白.但是这就是问题.我希望我们的关系能有结果.
Kate: I know.But that was the problem.I wanted it to go somewhere with you.
迈克:哦,哦,但是和埃迪,这就不是什么问题了?
Mike: Oh.Oh but with Eddie for some reason it's not a problem?
凯特:正确.
Kate: Exactly.
迈克:凯特,我不明白.我不明白.让我来告诉你一些事情.你知道吗?我碰巧.我碰巧.我处在这样一个世界,做我任何想做的,任何时间我需要的.但是事实上,事实上……(亲吻她).如果你没有注意自己的说话,我再来一次.
Mike: Kate, I don't get this.I do not get it.And let me tell you something.You know what?I'm happening.I'm happening.I am out there is this world doing whatever I want, whenever I want.And in fact, in fact...(Kisses her) And if you don't watch what you say I'll do it again.
凯特:迈克,你在干什么?
Kate: Mike, what are you doing?
迈克:我,我不知道.
Mike: I, I don't know.
麦琪:哦,杰森,瞧,他们在亲吻.不甜蜜吗?
Maggie: Oh Jason, look, they are kissing.Isn't it sweet?
杰森:那是他今天约会的第四个姑娘.
Jason: That's the forth girl he has been with today.
开萝尔:嗨,我从……回来了.
Carol: Hi.I'm home from that...
你们在监视我和男朋友在走廊约会,是吗?
You were spying on me and my date on the porch.Weren't you?
这太甜蜜了.你们很关心我.
This is so sweet.You do care.
杰森:我还能说什么,亲爱的?
Jason: What can I say honey?You caught us.
你逮住我们了.我想这种情况下谎言很适合.
I think a lie was in order in that case.
迈克:你知道,我,我讨厌和厌倦你追着要求我承担责任.还有我成长的诸如此类的话,你希望我有责任,和,而且事实上我没有遗憾我们的分手,(接吻)(接吻)一分钟.
Mike: You know, I, I was so sick and tired of you hounding me for
commitment.And all that stuff about me growing up,
you wanting me to be responsible
and, and in fact I haven't regretted our breakup for, (kiss), for (kiss) one minute
凯特:很好.我(接吻)也是.
Kate: Good.Me (kiss) either.
本:我真高兴我买了高倍望远镜.
Ben: I am so glad I bought the high powered binoculars.
迈克:那么我想今晚,我们从头再来?
Mike: So I guess tonight, we're starting over?
凯特:我也想.
Kate: I guess.
迈克:行.瞧,凯特,我们得进去告诉他们,我们之间的感情.我想,他们会理解.
Mike: Alright.Look Kate, we've got to go in there and tell them how we feel about each other.I mean, they'll understand.
凯特:嗨,
Kate: Hey, we just have to remember there are other people's feelings
我们要记得他们的感情在危险边缘.
at stake.
迈克:是.
Mike: Yeah.
蒂娜:七又八分之三.
Tina: Seven and three eights.
埃迪:你是怎么算的.
Eddie: How do you do it?
迈克:啊,啊,伙计们.
Mike: Uh, uh, guys.
蒂娜:终于来了.我能看出墙里面写的.你和我完了.
Tina: Here it comes.I can read the writing in the wall.You're done with me.
迈克:哦,蒂娜.
Mike: Oh Tina.
蒂娜:我应该已经知道你脚踩两只船,你来接我的时候,当时车里还有别的姑娘.
Tina: I should have known you were a two timer when you picked me up while you were with that other girl.
迈克:瞧,瞧,她比蒂娜对我不再有什么要紧了.
Mike: Look, look, she didn't matter to me any more than Tina does.
蒂娜:我不要紧?
Tina: I don't matter?
迈克:不,不,不.蒂娜,当然你要紧.
Mike: No, no, no.Tina of course you matter.
凯特:迈克!
Kate: Mike!
迈克:凯特,我应该怎么办.我不能伤她的心.
Mike: Kate, what am I supposed to do.I can't break her heart.
凯特:我能.
Kate: I can.
埃迪:我感觉被出卖了,迈克.你已经把这个女人卖给我了.
Eddie: I'm feeling betrayed here Mike.You sold me this woman.
凯特:什么?
Kate: What?
迈克:等等.我一角也没有拿.我把你送给他的.
Mike: Wait.I did not take a dime.I gave you to him.
凯特:哦!
Kate: Oh!
迈克:不,不.凯特,事情不像你听我说的那样.
Mike: No, no.Kate I didn't mean that the way it sounded.
蒂娜:就告诉我,是给我出租车钱,
Tina: Just tell me if I am getting cab fare or if I am in for
还是让我在这待一会.
the duration?
迈克:听着,听着,凯特.也许我们俩应该推迟到明天早上开始.
Mike: Look, look Kate.Maybe we should put off starting off until tomorrow.
凯特:不,我们不.不,事实上你可以忘记刚才在那继续的一切事情,因为我们结束了.再次.
Kate: No, lets not.No, in fact you can forget everything that went on out
there, because we are through.Again
埃迪:嗨.迈克.我明白你对这事十分恼火.我送蒂娜回家.
Eddie: Hey.Mike.I can see you are pretty upset about this.I'll take Tina home.
杰森:是的,我听到车道上怒气冲冲地鞋底的声音,
Jason: Yeah, well I just heard angry high heels on the drive way.
我熟悉那声音.
I know that sound.
迈克:嗨,大家伙.
Mike: Hey guys.
杰森:迈克.你妈妈刚把睡衣钩在那,那里.老房子看上去不错,嘿?
Jason: Mike.Your mum must have got her robe caught on, the thing.So the old room looks ok,hey?
迈克:我只想说,你们告诉我的一切对我今晚发生的事都不奏效.
Mike: I just want to say that nothing you have ever told me even came
因此我要责怪你们.
close to preparing me for what happened to me tonight.And I blame both of you.
你比她多,爸爸.
More you than her dad.
麦琪:怎么回事,迈克?
Maggie: What happened Mike?
迈克:我是有许多姑娘.许多姑娘.
Mike: Well I have got dozens of girls.Dozens of girls.
我甚至记不清她们的名字.我是说爸爸.你在树丛里.
I can't even keep their names straight.Imean dad.You were in the bushes.
你观察我和那姑娘.对吗?
You saw me with that girl.Right?
麦琪:杰森,偷窥是不是你的专业爱好?
Maggie: Jason, is peeping a full time hobby with you?
迈克:为什么究竟我就得放弃所有的乐趣呢?并不是有人让我放弃所有的乐趣,承担责任.不,我太不成熟了.
Mike: And why on earth would I want to give up all that fun?Not that anyone wants me togive up all that fun and make a commitment.No, I'm too immature.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,这是不是和凯特有点关系?
Maggie: Oh honey, does this have something to do with Kate?
迈克:妈妈,你怎么知道?
Mike: Mum, how did you know?
麦琪:母亲就是知道.
Maggie: A mother knows.
杰森:但是,迈克,我猜想你们本想重归于好,结果却没有成功.是吗?
Jason: But Mike, my guess is that you talked about getting back together and it just didn'twork.Hey?
迈克:你也知道!
Mike: You too!
杰森:父亲也就是知道.
Jason: Well a father knows too.
迈克:这没有意义了.我是说,
Mike: It just doesn't make sense.
我是想和凯特重归于好,
I mean, I want to get back together with Kate and I want tobe with her.
我想想和她在一起.我想每时每刻和她在一起.
I want to be with her every single second.
麦琪:哦,迈克,这是你的真心话.
Maggie: Oh Mike, that's your heart talking.
迈克:但是另一方面我也喜欢别的我认为有趣的姑娘.好吧,
Mike: But on the other hand I want to be with every other girl I find
所有任何地方的姑娘.我只是不知道做什么?
interesting?Ok, allwomen everywhere.I just don't know what to do.
杰森:那是因为你有心理暗示,迈克.
Jason: Well that's because you have a hint of a conscience Mike.
迈克:我能摆脱它吗?
Mike: Well can I get rid of it?
杰森:没有这样的运气.
Jason: No such luck.
麦琪:没有这样的运气.
Maggie: No such luck!
杰森:麦琪,行了,女人的苦难是帮不了迈克的.瞧,在每个男人的心里,有两种基本冲动.一方面是寻找一个终身伴侣,与她共建美好生活的冲动.
Jason: Maggie please.Female bitterness isn't going to help Mike.
另一方面,从一棵树到另一棵树,看哪棵树摇晃.而实际上第二种冲动十分强烈,所以社会制定了法规,迫使一个男人,不管他有多么强壮,屈服和最终结婚.
Look, in every male there
are two basic drives.You know that on the one hand is that drive to
nest with a single mate and build a beautiful life together.On the other hand
kind of hopping from tree to tree to see what shakes.In fact that second
drive is so strong that society has created rules to force a man, no matter
how strong he is, to capitulate and eventually get married
麦琪:屈服!哦,我们真幸运.
Maggie: Capitulate!Oh, lucky us.
杰森:科学事实,麦琪.
Jason: These are scientific facts Maggie.
麦琪:杰森,这是一条很长的路去验证一个徘徊的眼睛.
Maggie: Jason, this is a long way to go to justify a wandering eye.
杰森:我以为我们已经足够亲密,所以与儿子分享一些真理,
Jason: I thought we were close enough that I could share these truths
在你面前.瞧,
with my son, in front of you.
随着有足够的时间和经验,你会获得智慧,
Look, with enough time and experience you are going to achieve the wisdom
迈克,来明白放弃成百个,上千个,
to see.Mike, that by giving up these hundreds, thousands, millions of girls,
上百万个姑娘以后,你会在一个姑娘身上得到更多.
that you are going to get, so much more with one woman.
真的,当遥远的那天来的时候,
Really, and when that distant day comes,
你会说"我明白了".这样你不会牺牲一件事情.
you are going to be saying "I got it".And you won't be sacrificing a thing.
迈克:我明白了.
Mike: I got it.
杰森:等等,等等,
Jason: Wait, wait, wait.How can this be that distant day?
等等.遥远的将来会怎么样?现在你才想了不到五秒钟.
You've been thinking about it for five seconds.
迈克:因为,这足够了.
Mike: Because, it was enough.
杰森:等等,等等,等等.你并没有想明白.你一天内已经和四个漂亮女人约会.
Jason: Wait, wait, wait.You are not thinking straight.You have been with four gorgeouswomen in one day.
迈克:是的,爸爸.我知道你说的意思了.我告诉你.我明白了!
迈克:嗨,听着;听我说完以后你再说,好吗?我现在准备好了.我要和你在一起.听着,我不再是个长不大的大孩子了.我做好了承担责任的准备,凯特.这是什么号码?听着,我真抱歉……迈克.你好,利萨,我也很高兴见到你.听着,我得走了.对,我的声音是受过训练的.我是演员.你是干什么的?哦哇!你是收费所的收费员和贴身内衣模特?太伤心了,我开车时怎么没见过你.哇,你的笑声真有感染力.你怎么会笑得这样有魅力?她们怎么会笑得这样有魅力?啊,嗨,听着,你能否稍等一会,我要去向我爸爸解释一点事情?好的.你还在么?
00:21:16,800
Mike: Yeah dad.I have got what you are saying.I'm telling you.I got it! Mike: Hi listen; don't say a word until I'm finished, right? I am ready now. I want to be with you. Look I am through with being a terminal teenager. I am ready to make a commitment Kate. What number is this? Listen I am really sorry.....Mike. Hi Lisa, it's nice to meet you too. Listen, I got to go. Well yes, I have had some voice training. I'm an actor. What do you do? Oh wow! You are a toll booth collector and a lingerie model? Well it makes me kind of sad I do my motoring with exact change. Wow man, you've got a great laugh. Why do you have to have such a great laugh? Why do they all have to have such great laughs? Uh, hey listen, could you hold on while I go ask my dad to explain something? Alright. You still there?